VIKASH KUMAR MISHRA

Java Full Stack Developer @TCS

DOB: 29 Apr 1997

Email ID: vkmishra2904@gmail.com LinkedIn: vikash-kumar-mishra-8176b1187

GitHub: github.com/avi-in Website: vkmprotfolio.netlify.app

Contact: 8269999269

Profile

A skilled, experienced & self-motivated Software Developer having 2.8+ years of experience in development and maintenance of enterprise level web applications using the latest tools, technologies and best practices. I have a strong understanding of Java, Spring boot, Angular, Hibernate, Data JPA, and familiar with Agile Development methodology to work in a collaborative environment.

Relevant Experience

Full Stack Developer @TCS (Client - Jaguar Land Rover)

March 2022 - Present // Pune

- Application Development, UAT Bug Fixing, Performance enhancements.
- Developed and maintained enterprise-level web applications using the Spring framework
 Implemented business logic using Java and Spring Boot.
- Created Responsive Single Page Application (SPA) using Angular Framework, Type Script, Bootstrap, CSS & Prime NG library.
- Developed and Integrated Restful API to Web Application for CRUD operation using MySQL as Data Source.
- Implemented Data import/Export functionality using Spring Batch, Authentication & Authorization using Spring Security.
- Created Routing, Breadcrumbs, Dynamic form fields, table, pagination, route protection functionality based upon user role using Angular Guard.

Angular Developer @TCS (Client - Jaguar Land Rover)

Nov 2020 - Feb 2022 // Pune

- Understanding Stakeholder functional requirements and translating that into code.
- Designed and developed creative intuitive user interfaces for application using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript & Bootstrap.
- Designed & created new components for user interaction with back-end application using prime Ng library.
- Integrated RESTful APIs in Application using Angular HTTP Client Module, and uses RxJs operator for data manipulation as per requirement.
- Implemented multiple modules in application with Angular lazy loading technique to enhance application performance.
- Modified existing components by adding new functionalities, altering that particular component's existing functionalities without impacting application others existing functionality.

Projects

IOT Based Garbage Monitoring System

 Created IOT Based Garbage Monitoring System using Arduino, Node MCU, PIR Sensor for real time garbage monitoring.

Hospital Management System

- It is an application for booking appointments, scheduling appointment, tracking all scheduled appointment for a particular day.
- Technology Used: Spring boot, Spring -security, Angular, MySQL, Swagger for documentation and API testing.

Personal Portfolio Website

- Created a portfolio website for personal use.
- Technology Used: HTML, CSS, ReactJS.

Skills

Programming Languages

Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML,CSS

Frameworks & Libraries

Spring, Spring boot, Spring Data JPA, Hibernate, MYSQL, Angular, Bootstrap, Prime Ng, RxJs

Tools & Platforms

Git, Maven, Docker, Kubernetes

Certification

Programming in Java

Certificate from IIT Kharagpur in GOLD Category (NPTEL).

Java Full Stack Development Certificate from TCS.

Hacker Rank Skill Certification
Hacker Rank Java basic certification

Signal & System

NPTEL Certificate from IIT Kanpur

AWS CDA

AWS CDA Certificate from Udemy.

Education

LNCT, BHOPAL

2016 - 2020

Bachelor of Engineering **(B.E)** in Electronics & Communication Engineering **(ECE)** with Honors Degree.

Language

English

Hindi